Yesterday one boy stood up and asked Me a question,
昨天有个男孩站起来问我︰
that "When we are such a yoga bhoomi,
我们是如此的一片瑜伽之地
we are such a holy country,
如此神圣的国家
why is it that all the discoveries in the science
为什么所有科学上的发现
are made in the West?"
都在西方？
"Very good question," I said.
「非常好的问题。」我说
I said, "That is the knowledge of the tree,
我回答：「这是树的知识
as I have told you; that's the knowledge of the tree.
我告诉过你，这是树的知识
And what have they achieved is now the end of it,
他们（西方）成就的是树的末梢
and now they want to know the knowledge of the roots.
现在他们想知道根的知识
That's why they are here."
所以才来这里
So to know the knowledge of the roots,
要了解根的知识
first of all we must have humility about it.
我们先要怀着谦虚的态度
We have not known this knowledge yet,
我们还未认识这门知识
never known what is in the Kingdom of God.
也从不知道神的国度有什么
As Krishna has said, this tree grows downward
正如克里希纳所说，这棵树是向下生长的
and the roots are in the brain - clearly.
根在脑袋里---很清楚
So it is an ascent to go to the roots,
所以这是朝向根的升进
it's a different style.
是以不同的方式
Kundalini has to rise upward to go to the roots,
灵量必须向上升到达根
and to enter into the roots
要到达根
what we have to do is to know about it.
我们要做的就是要了解它
Now all these things, like I said yesterday
现在所有这些事情，像我昨天说过的
that you put on bindi.
你要在额头点上红点（bindi）
Now this is also - thank God,
现在这也是----感谢天
despite all changes in the Bible,
尽管有人把圣经窜改
it's written in the Bible
圣经里仍有写下
that you'll be known by the mark you'll be carrying.
你身上的标记代表你
Now let's see how many are courageous, even in India,
现在让我们看看，即使在印度
to carry this mark.
有多少人勇于点上这标记
That's why you people catch so fast,
那就是为何你们那么快受感染
one of the reasons why you people catch.
其中一个你们受感染的原因
First of all the eyes are not steady.
首先，眼睛闪烁不定
You are not used to the steady eyes, you see,
你们不习惯有稳定的眼睛，你看
as the Indians have very steady eyes.
印度人就有很稳定的眼睛
They are, from childhood they are taught,
他们从小受教导：
"Where is your attention?"
你的注意力哪里去了？
All the time they are asked, "Where is your attention?"
每时每刻都有人问他们：「你的注意力哪里去了？」
There are some Western Sahaja yogis standing at the back.
马拉地语︰有一些西方的霎哈嘉瑜伽士站在后面
Please give them a chair to sit,
请给他们椅子，让他们坐下
since they are not able to sit on the ground.
他们不习惯坐在地上。
So where is your attention?
你的注意力哪里去了？
Now the attention is so disturbed all the time
现在，注意力时时刻刻都受到干扰
and that's why you catch very fast,
这就是你很快受到感染的原因
and when you catch from your eyes,
若你的眼睛受感染
it goes through your Agnya Chakra.
它会从额轮进入
Now this is the protection of Agnya Chakra;
这是保护额轮
it's actually the blood of Christ that you wear.
你实际上是点上基督的血
But people must have that courage.
人们应当有这份勇气去点上它
They'll wear a cross, but not this.
他们会穿戴十字架，却不是这个
In the Western countries it's very difficult
在西方国家，人们很难
for people to have that much courage to put on this.
有勇气点上这个
They will have excuses,
他们藉多嘴多舌
"Mother, we'll lose our jobs," this, that.
「母亲，我们会丢掉工作。」这样、那样
Every sort of an excuse is there.
有各种各样的借口
But if you are courageous people,
若你有勇气
then you have to start wearing it some time.
你就会开始点上它一段时间
Maybe in the night you start first, then in the daytime.
或许你先在晚上开始，然后在白天
Slowly, slowly you can creep into it.
慢慢你就会接受它
That's the only thing I think you people have to wear
我想那是你们唯一要带上的东西
- that's important.
那是非常重要的
That will be a good idea, because you will not catch.
点上它会是个好主意，你因此不会受感染
Because you go outside, your attention is outside,
因为你外出，你的注意力在外
you see what's happening outside, the atmosphere is bad.
你看到外面有什么事在发生，那种气氛并不好
Moreover, if you put this on it will not only protect you,
更何况，如果你额上点上红点，它不单保护你
but also protect others.
也保护其他人
They will have a new idea.
他们就会有新的想法
After all, you will dress up like them,
毕竟，你打扮得与他们一样
you are just like them - you have to be.
你就像他们----你必须如此
But you have to protect,
不过你得保护自己
and for protection you have to wear something like that.
为了保护自己，你必须要点上像那样的东西
I found that when I went first to England
当我第一次来英国的时候
they used to laugh at Me, looking at My red mark.
我发现他们常常嘲笑我，盯着我的红点
I mean, if they wear lipsticks it's all right,
我是说他们涂上口红就没问题
even if they are clowns, if they are hippies,
即使是小丑、嬉皮士
they are punks, it's all right;
奇装异服，全都没问题
but if you wear a proper thing which is scientific,
但若你点上符合科学且正当的东西就有问题
it's most scientific.
即使那是最科学化的
So to understand the science of the roots
要了解根的科学
you must understand what it means,
你必须了解它代表什么
why this culture is like this:
为什么这个文化是这样的
because it is more towards the roots,
因为它较朝向根
the movement is not towards the tree.
而不是移向树
And the tree, where it has ended up?
那么这棵树，终点在哪里？
Beyond the Mooladhara Chakra.
超越根轮
So now they are returning back.
所以现在他们都调回头了
To go from the leaf to the roots is very difficult,
要从叶走往根是很困难的
but to go from the roots to the leaves is easier.
但从根走往叶却比较容易
So for this ascent we have to be humble,
所以为了升进，我们必须谦卑
to know about the knowledge - knowledge about the roots.
以便了解根的知识
Now why they put on, all of them, is this is the reason,
现在他们所有人的额上都点上红点
that to protect your Agnya. First of all there's no entry.
这是为了保护额轮。首先是没有入口
That's why, once an Indian gets realization, he ascends.
这就是为何印度人一旦得到自觉，就会升进
He doesn't go on catching again;
不会再受感染
I mean, this doesn't happen here.
我是说这样的事情在这里不会发生
This is one of the things one has to do.
这是其中一件我们必须做的事
Now the second thing is the puja.
其二是崇拜
The puja has its effect on everyone,
按照每个人的深度
but according to your depth;
崇拜对每个人都会起作用
and that's for that you have to have shraddha, faith.
因此你必须有shraddha(坚信)，信念
If your mind is still thinking,
如果你的脑袋仍在思考
you cannot achieve much in puja.
你不会在崇拜里有多少收获
While for Indians, to attend a puja is the highest.
对印度人来说，参加崇拜是件大事
They don't mind My lecture, anything;
无论我讲什么，他们都不会计较
if they miss the program, doesn't matter,
如果他们错过了某场节目，不要紧
any music program is all right,
任何音乐会也不要紧
any kind of discomfort is all right
任何不舒适也没事
- as long as they can attend to puja.
只要他们能够参加崇拜
Today people have come
今天人们
from two hundred to three hundred miles for this puja,
老远从二、三百里
all the way,
来崇拜
because they know this is the knowledge of the roots.
因为他们知道这是根的知识
For that you have to do the puja.
为此你必须做崇拜
If you have to ascend, you have to do it.
如果你要升进，就得做崇拜
But you are still in the same level;
可是你还是在同样的层次
if you are still thinking about the tree style,
如果你仍是想着树的模式
then you'll go downward.
便会往下掉
To move inward, you have to have all these instruments.
要往内移，你必须有这些工具
One of them is of puja.
其一是崇拜
Now for puja, are we prepared?
现在，我们是否已经为崇拜准备就绪？
Are we in that mind,
我们心里是否在想
whatever time it has to start, will start?
不论崇拜何时开始，随时都能开始？
First of all, we have tied our watches quite tight.
首先，我们把手表绑得紧紧的
Thank God, I lost My watch last night!
感谢天，昨晚我遗失了手表！
So now the watches have tied us up so much
手表把我们绑得这么紧
that now eleven o'clock puja means eleven o'clock.
如果说崇拜在十一点开始，就必定得在十一点开始
It's not like that - it depends on.
不是这样的----什么时候开始是随缘的
It is the natural growth of our being,
这是我们的存在体自然的成长
it is the natural working of our growing.
我们的成长是自然的
When I came here, you'll be amazed,
当我来到这里，你会感到惊讶
all My right side was paralyzed, absolutely paralyzed.
我的右边身体麻痹了，完全麻痹了
Right foot was paralyzed, I just couldn't move My legs,
右脚麻痹了，我的腿就是不能动
and all the feet had become like a fossilized stuff,
整只脚掌好像成了化石
and I didn't know what was happening.
我也不知道是什么一回事
The reason is, everybody has been thinking too much.
原因是，大家都想得太多了
Now the attention should be how we are,
我们的注意力应当专注在我们是怎样的人
what are we doing about ourselves, that's very important;
我们为自己做了些什么，这些才重要
how far we have achieved.
我们有什么成就
But on the contrary, the attention is disturbed
可是相反，我们的注意力却受
by many things. One of them may be the marriages,
很多事物干扰。其一可能是婚姻
that marriages have to take place,
比如说要办婚事
what's going to happen and all that.
有什么会发生，诸如此类
But at puja time it has no meaning.
在崇拜的时候这些事情都是毫无意义的
Nothing has importance than but to develop yourself,
没有什么比发展自己更重要
and this is what it is:
就是这样
at this time you have to develop your roots.
在这个时候，你必须发展你的根
And to develop your roots,
要发展你的根
it's a different science altogether.
是另一门完全不同的科学
The another thing is that you can achieve
另一件事是你能以逼迫
the movement of the tree by aggressiveness, by aggressing.
强迫的方式来达成树的运动
But when you aggress in the human mind,
可是当脑袋有逼迫人的想法
then you are drawn towards the Mooladhara more,
你便更加走向根轮
towards the gravity force,
走向地心吸力
and you go down towards the dead;
走向死物
the materialism starts coming up.
物质主义就开始冒起
Because it's upside down, human growth is upside down.
因为它是倒置的，人类就以倒过来的方式来成长
You know the brain is here, not at the feet.
你知道脑袋在这儿，不是在双脚
It starts from the brain, the growth starts from the brain;
它是从脑袋开始，生长是从脑袋开始
as you know as doctors that the whole thing is here
作为一名医生，你知道整体是在这儿
and the nerves go down, they do not start from the feet.
神经是往下走的，它们不是从双脚开始
So when you start putting your attention to your
所以一旦你把注意力放在
outward growth, you go towards materialism automatically.
你外在的成长，便会自自然然的走向物质主义
Then you find matter has nothing to do,
跟着你发现物质对你一点作用也没有
you have fossilized yourself. So then you come back.
你把自己石化了，所以你才回来
Now you have to change your attitude completely
现在你必须完全改变你对这
towards this new learning,
新的学习抱的态度
and this new learning is that you have to
你的态度
develop a humble attitude, first of all.
先要谦卑
And secondly, what are we going to achieve
其二，透过学习
in our ascent through learning the different tantra,
不同的tantra，即机制
the mechanism, the divine mechanism - how to work it out.
神圣的机制，我们能怎样提升自己----怎样能把它成就
The person who is extremely efficient in the other field
精通其他领域的人很可能对这个领域
might become completely inefficient in this field,
一筹莫展
absolutely useless: possessed, aggressive, good for nothing,
完全无用武之地；被鬼附、欺压人、一事无成
hot-tempered, hot-tempered, and also devoid of any love,
坏脾气、脾气差，还丧失了爱心
affection, compassion.
情感、慈悲
Like they were shocked to hear
比如说当听到
that people kill their children in England,
在英国有人杀掉自己的孩子
they couldn't believe it.
他们(印度人)感到震惊，没法相信
They can't believe even one child killed like that.
他们不能相信有人会杀掉孩子
They think that English are perfect people,
他们以为英国人是完美的
how can they kill their children?
怎会杀死自己的孩子？
They are very perfect according to Indians.
对印度人而言，他们(英国人)是非常完美的
Indians have no idea as to what kind of life they lead there.
印度人没法想象他们过的是怎样的生活
So when I told them,
所以当我告诉他们：
"You are sadly mistaken, they are very unhappy people.
你们错得很离谱，他们是很不开心的人
Don't think that by developing radios and all these things,
不要以为发明了收音机和其他东西
they are happy. They are all mad.
他们就会快乐。他们全是疯子
They sit before the television,
他们坐在电视机前面
then they can't do without it, they become televisions.
生活不能没有电视，他们变成电视机
And the television is exploiting them,
电视机在剥削他们
putting wrong ideas into their heads,
把错误的想法灌入他们的脑袋
and they're brainwashed, they are very conditioned"
他们被洗脑了，令他们有很多思想制约
- they can't believe it.
他们不能相信
They can't believe that people could be that cruel
不能相信西方人能这样残忍
in the West; because the growth is towards materialism,
因为生长是朝向物质主义
so they are becoming gross, insensitive, immoral,
所以他们变得粗糙、反应迟钝、不道德
and also devoid of any compassion and love.
也丧失了一切怜悯和爱
So first of all, as I said yesterday you should say,
那么首先，正如我昨天提及，你应说：
"I'm not French" - you should say, "I am not a Westerner."
「我不是法国人。」---你应说：「我不是西方人。」
Let's see, that may work out, work out better,
让我们看看，这样可能会成就到，成就得更好
"I'm not a Westerner." Maybe when you enter a university
「我不是西方人。」或许当你进大学----
- supposing you are in Oxford University
就如你从牛津大学
and then you go to the Cambridge University,
转学到剑桥大学
you have to wear the badge of the Cambridge University.
你必须带上剑桥大学的校徽
In the same way now you have changed your nationality,
你现在同样已经改变了国籍
I think you should say, "I'm not a Westerner now anymore."
我想你该说：「我再也不是西方人。」
Maybe the passport might say anything, doesn't matter.
或许你的护照可能仍是那样，不要紧
But you have a special privilege in India as Sahaja yogis,
在印度，你知道作为霎哈嘉瑜伽士是享有特权的
you know that. As Sahaja yogis the government
政府就因为你是霎哈嘉瑜伽士
has accepted you. If you want to stay here forever,
而接纳你，如果你想永远留在这里
they'll have no objection.
他们不会反对
So this, whatever is now we think works out
所以，我们认为能在
on the tree level, has to be changed.
树的层面成就事情的想法必须改变
Here everything becomes united, synthesized.
在这里一切都融合一致、聚合在一起
The whole tree is synthesized in a seed.
整棵树聚合在一颗种子里
So if you have to become the root,
所以如果你要成为根
you have to come down to the position where,
便要谦卑下来
how to synthesize. Now grouping is a wrong thing.
下降至一个能聚合的位置。联群结党是错的
If you group yourself as English, this, that,
如果你归类自己为英国人、这个、那个
or Indians or anything, is wrong.
或印度人，又或其他什么，都是错的
In Sahaja Yoga we don't believe in all that.
在霎哈嘉瑜伽，我们不相信所有这些
There is no differentiation
这个霎哈嘉瑜伽士和
between one Sahaja yogi and another Sahaja yogi,
那个霎哈嘉瑜伽士毫无差别
because it is Vishwa Dharma.
因为那是普世正法
But we say this is Vishwa Dharma,
我们说这是普世正法
but we are not out of it as yet,
我们却还没有跳出来
we are not yet in the same pendal where we should be.
仍未到达我们应该到达的同样的pendal层次
We still separate, we are still different,
我们仍是分裂的，仍是有差别的
we have to still mix up from one country to another country.
我们仍要与各个不同的国家融合一起
We have to all become one with each other,
我们必须全都融合在一起
understanding each other;
互相了解
then only the problems of the West will go away.
只有这样才能解决西方的问题
As a result of this right-sided movement
这右脉运动的结果
I feel that people are really becoming idiotic.
使我觉得人们真是变成白痴了
I categorize them as idiotic or stupid, and all that.
我把他们归类为白痴或笨蛋，诸如此类
I mean I don't how,
我是说我不知道
what categories they will fall into later on,
之后他们会归入什么类别
where there have been not such categories before.
一个以往未有的类别
I mean, they might form a new dimension of stupidity.
我是说，他们可能组成一种新的笨蛋类别
This is what I feel,
这就是我的感受
that unless and until you now learn about this new yantra,
除非你现在学懂这个新的yantra(机制)
the new method:
新的方法
in that you don't see to the physical comfort,
就是你不会理会身体的舒适
you don't see to the so-called emotional pampering.
不会理会所谓的情绪娇宠
All these things you don't see,
你不会理会这些
but where do you go - into innocence.
你会往哪儿去----走向纯真
The quality of the matter itself is innocence, the essence.
物质的本质是纯真，是精髓
So the quality, I should say,
所以品质，我应该说
or the essence of everything you become.
你成为万物的精髓
You become the essence.
你成为精髓
But for that you have to move inward,
为此你要往内移
and the inward movement is only possible
当你了解、尊重
when you understand and respect,
并且因能做这些事情而感到荣幸时
and think yourself privileged to be able to do all this.
才有可能往内移
But you have to understand why I tell you.
不过你应该了解我为何要告诉你
I have nothing to gain out of you.
我从你身上不会有什么得益
Now one should not think I'm trying to make you Indians,
不要以为我想把你变成印度人
but supposing you wear here three-piece suit and a tie,
试想一下，你穿上三件式的套装，结上领带
what will happen to you?
有什么会发生？
I mean, you'll all get boils in the body.
我是说，你的身体会沸腾起来
According to the climate you have to change,
你应该随着气候而转变
and you enjoy this dress very much
你享受这种服装
because it is very comfortable.
因为穿上它你感到舒适
You enjoy the river baths, it's very comfortable.
你享受在河里沐浴，因为沐浴令你舒服
In this country that suits you better.
在这个国家里，这样对你是最合适不过
So in the same way this new life that we are entering in,
所以在我们进入这新生的同时
we have to understand that the outside is not important
也必须了解外表并不重要
- the inside is important.
内涵才重要
And for that whatever is to be done outside,
因此，无论外在需要做些什么
we have to do it, we have to do it.
我们也要去做
We have to learn it, we have to understand it,
我们要学习它，了解它
what is this, what is that.
这是什么，那是什么
Now because you are scientists, you are Westerners,
因为你是科学家，你是西方人
you have an advantage over Indians I should say,
我可以说你比印度人有优势
or in science, all right.
或在科学方面有优势
In this science they have an advantage over you.
对吧。但这门科学他们(印度人)却比你优胜
Doesn't matter, it's all right.
不要紧，没问题的
They chose this place to come in,
他们选这里来
you chose that place to come in;
你们选那里来
because you're brave people I think, first of all,
我认为你们都很勇敢，此其一
and secondly that you wanted to do some good there maybe.
其二，也许你们想做些好事
But for that you must learn.
不过为此你必须学习
Like we say our scientists here are brave people
就像我们说这里的科学家都很勇敢
that they are trying to learn science,
他们(印度人)尝试学习科学
they want to go abroad and learn about it
想到国外学习，然后把学懂的
and bring some science to us.
科学知识带给我们
In the same way now you are the ambassadors
你们(西方人)同样是
from all these countries, of divinity,
来自这些国家的使者，神性的
ambassadors of divinity. You have to carry divinity,
神性的使者。你必须具备神性
because it has been worked out in this country.
因为它在这个国家已经有所成就
As you can see clearly it is so, accept it;
正如你也很清楚地看见了它就是这样，接受它吧
there's nothing to feel bad about it.
对它没有什么坏感觉
Because you're attached to a certain nationality
因为你执着于你的国籍
and all that you think, there's nothing to feel bad.
执着于所有你在意的事，没有必要有任何坏的感觉
In India people feel very proud
在印度，人们会因为能到
if they have to go abroad to learn science.
国外学习科学而感到很自豪
Even if they are vegetarians,
即使他们是素食者
they don't mind doing biology dissection
他们也不介意做生物解剖
or anything because it is science, it is knowledge.
或类似的事，就因为它是科学、是知识
So for knowledge's sake you have to do all these things.
所以为了学习，你必须做这些事
And once you realize that for knowledge's sake
一旦你意识到你是为了知识
you are working it out, it's going to help you a lot.
而把它成就到，便会对你大有帮助
This one, this today's puja, it has a special meaning
这个，今天这个崇拜，有特别的意义
because yesterday was Datta Jayanti,
因为昨天是 Datta Jayanti
means the birth of Dattatreya.
即达陀陀里耶(Dattatreya)的生日
And you know the story of Dattatreya,
你们大部分人都知道
most of you know the story of Dattatreya,
达陀陀里耶的故事
that Brahma, Vishnu, Mahesha tried to take a test
就是梵天婆罗摩、毗湿奴、湿婆神(Mahesha)想通过
of Adi Shakti, called Anasuya.
太初之母的考验，叫做【Anasuya】
They came to Her place and asked Her for alms.
他们来到她的地方，要求她施舍(alms)
And it's supposed to be a great privilege in India
在印度，施舍他人被视为
to give alms to others,
极大的荣幸
to - I mean, it's a great privilege to attend to guests,
我是说，照顾客人是很大的荣幸
it's a great privilege to be generous,
慷慨是很大的荣幸
it's a great privilege to distribute things to others.
分派物品给他人是很大的荣幸
It's a great privilege.
那是很大的荣幸
Like yesterday, you see, My sari for this puja
就像昨天，你看，我把这个崇拜的纱丽
was left somewhere out.
留在某个地方
So I had bought a sari for some lady here, so she said,
所以我为这里一些女士买了纱丽，她因此说：
"I would like this sari to be presented at the puja."
我希望这纱丽能在崇拜里送出
But I said, "I'll return it you."
可是我说：「我会把它还给你。」
She said, "That's a greater privilege, too."
她说：「这也算是个很大的荣幸。」
They didn't mind the sari was left out,
他们不在意纱丽被遗留了
they said it's a greater privilege - the attitude.
他们说这是个极大的荣幸---看她的态度
So the attitude is to be changed,
所以要改变态度
that so far we are going downward,
到目前为止我们一直往下跌
now the attitude should be upward.
现在要抱的态度应是往上升
And for that, we have to understand
为此，我们要了解该
the method by which we are going to climb up.
用什么方法往上爬
Like you have to go to the mountains,
就像你要爬山
you must know how to do the mountaineering.
便要懂得爬山技能
You cannot just state yourself, "Now I'm going to Himalayas"
你不能就这么说：「现在我要去喜马拉雅山。」
- nobody will allow you.
没人会让你去
So one has to qualify, and in qualifying
所以你要具备资格，为了合乎资格
you have to have that humility, otherwise it won't work out.
你必须要谦卑，不然是成就不了
So I have to make a very clear statement,
我要非常清楚的说明
that you change your nationality
你要把你的国籍
from the worldly nationality to the heavenly nationality.
从世俗的国籍转为上天的国籍
And there, whatever is needed we'll be doing it,
无论需要做什么，我们也要去做
we'll be accepting it, we'll be managing it.
也要去接受，也要去处理
For that you don't have to change anything like that,
因此，你不需像这样改变什么
but you have to transform yourself into a new personality;
你只要把自己转化成新的人格
new personality, where you are safe.
新的人格，那么你便能安全
Now just see, putting on that, how much Agnya has come down
现在只要看看，把那个点上，额轮降下了多少
- just see.
只看看
My foot was paralyzed, absolutely paralyzed when I walked in.
我双脚都麻痹了，当我进来时，双脚完全麻痹
I couldn't walk. I didn't know how I was going to take bath.
我走不动。我不知道我能怎样洗澡
I had to massage it, and then it came down.
我要按摩双脚，它才松弛下来
So just see putting that, just see that, how powerful it is.
所以看看，只是点上它，它是多么有力量
See - vibrations started flowing.
看---生命能量开始流动
But people are somehow in the West very much frightened
可是西方人不知何故非常害怕
that they will lose their nationality.
会失去自己的国籍
I mean, because - I feel, because the way they went all out
我是说，因为…我感到是因为他们倾尽全力
to destroy all the world and to destroy them,
去摧毁整个世界，摧毁自己
and put their own nationality on others.
把他们的国籍强加在他人身上
If you go to America - like yesterday I said,
如果你到美国，就像昨天我说过的：
"Thank God Columbus did not go to India,
感谢天，哥伦布没有来印度
he went …" I said, "Thank God, Hanumana pushed him
他去了……」我说：「感谢天，哈努曼把他
on the other side.
推到另一边
Otherwise we all would have been finished here, this … "
不然我们所有人都会完蛋，这个…
You see, poor man, he didn't want to do all that,
你看，可怜的家伙，他没想过要这么做
but all those followed him just went and finished.
可是他的随从却把一切了结
You can't find one aboriginal,
你找不到一个土著
one person from those old Indians in Argentina.
一个阿根廷的老印第安人也没有
I went to Argentina and they said,
我到阿根廷，他们说：
"In the museum you can find them"- just imagine.
「你能在博物馆里找到他们。」，试想像
Not only Argentina but also other places,
不单阿根廷，其他地方也一样
like I went to Chile: not a single person.
就像我到智利：一个也没有
Only in Bolivia I found some of them, that's all.
我只能在玻利维亚找到他们，就只有这么多了
But it is such a mixture there too,
可是那边也是混种的
because I think the people ran away to the hills
因为我想人们是逃到山上去
and managed themselves.
想办法生存
And whatever picture they have put about them,
他们无论怎样都会被人家
as if they are the cruel.
描绘成残暴之徒
Poor things, they have been all killed
可怜的家伙，白人确实
absolutely by white men, no doubt about it.
杀掉他们全部人，毋庸置疑
It's horrible to go and kill others, go into their land,
杀害他们是很可怕的，进入他们的土地
occupy it because you have got machinery, everything,
占领他们的土地，只因为你们(西方人)拥有机械，拥有一切
you can kill all of them.
你们能把他们全杀掉
All this has been done.
这一切已成定局
Now we are entering into a new era where we have to love.
如今我们在进入需要去爱的新时代
We don't have to aggress, we have to embrace.
我们不该欺压凌人，而是要包容接受人
This is another era altogether.
这是个全新的时代
That aggression of Napoleon is over now.
拿破仑的强横霸道的年代已经过去
It's a new thing we have started, into another world,
我们开创了新天地
when we have to get more people,
必须让更多人来
we have to synthesize the whole thing.
将整体融合为一
And when you aggress, you start analyzing
挑衅侵略的行为令你开始分析
- nothing to analyze.
没有什么需要分析
Are you feeling better now?
你现在感到好点吗？
Put on little bigger one.
额上红点画大一点
See, you have a big forehead, then put on big,
你的额头宽大，就画大一点吧
the very big - why do you put the little, small one?
为何画得那么小？
… on her head.
…在她的额头。
Fashion should not be done in these things.
这些事情
There should be no fashioning
不用追潮流
as far as your religious duties are concerned,
就宗教的礼仪而言
you should not. There is nothing like fashion.
你不应该讲究时尚
Fashion is a human affair, it's not divine.
时尚是人为的，不是上天的
Look at these trees, how do they fashion themselves?
看看这些树木，它们如何令自己时尚？
Towards the sun. Every leaf is exposed to the sun,
它们都朝向太阳，每片树叶都暴露于阳光下
every leaf; because it has to get chlorophyll,
因为它们要吸收阳光来制造叶绿素
it has to get the power of the sun in itself,
它们必须取得太阳的能量
so the every leaf is towards the sun.
所以每片叶都向着太阳
They don't do any fashions, do they?
它们有否追逐时尚潮流，有吗？
So another point is the individualism
另一点，来自西方的个人主义
that is started in the West is nonsense.
是荒谬的
To show off that "I'm something different,"
夸耀自己为「与众不同」
you become stupid.
只会令你变得愚笨
But to be one with everyone
真正的个人主义是
is the real individualism, I think.
你能与每一个人融合，化异为同
To be like everyone is the best.
能配合每一个人是最好的
It's very difficult, it's very difficult
这却是很难做到
to become one with everyone, because ego is so much.
因为自我太大
Some people have ego which hurts others,
有些人的自我总是伤害人
and some have whose ego is hurt - both just the same.
而有些人则是自我受到伤害 – 两者都一样
So to overcome all these things,
我们要去掉往下坠的态度
forget about that kind of attitude of descending downward.
才能克服这些问题
But for the ascent whatever is required
就升进而言，我们
is you look upward to God, look upward to Him
需要仰望神
with complete faith - shraddha.
以绝对的坚信仰望神- Shraddha
Then I don't have to touch you, you need not see Me.
故此我不用碰你，你也不用来见我
It exists everywhere, you can get the blessings everywhere.
它无所不在，无论你在哪里都能得到祝福
You don't have to do anything special for it
你不必煞费苦心
- just that shraddha.
只需要坚信
But for that, certain mechanisms are to be put right,
为此你必须纠正内在某些系统
specially the Agnya needs repairs, quite a lot.
尤其是额轮，要好好的修补它
That wheel is out of gear, and that must be put right.
这个轮穴已运作不灵，必须修补它
Mr. Patankar was yesterday was rather angry
昨天，帕坦伽先生
with the so-called educated people.
对那些所谓受过教育的人感到很生气
They are educated in English language, that's the problem,
问题出在他们是受英语教育
the language is like that.
而英语的性质就是如此
They think no end of themselves.
令他们自以为是
He said, "They didn't touch Your feet."
他说：「他们不会触摸你的莲足。」
If they learn English language they will not touch My feet,
他们若学习英语，便不会触摸我的莲足
because in English language touching the feet
因为在英语里，触摸别人的脚
is regarded as something horrible, I think.
被认为是件可怕呕心的事，我想
That's why he felt very sad about it.
这就是为何帕坦伽先生感到十分难过
But this is all architecture has come from England,
这些建筑技术都是来自英国
everything has come from Germany or from France.
一切都是来自德国或法国
Our telephones have come from France.
印度的电话是法国制造的
No wonder they work like this!
怪不得这么差劲
It's all the French who brought this,
全是从法国购入
and again they have got a big - I don't know,
他们还订了很多，我不知道
if I meet Rajiv Gandhi I'll tell him
如果我遇见首相拉吉夫
that at least don't give telephones to French.
我会告诉他别向法国人购买电话
They has given such a big, very big order to the French.
他们已向法国订了大批货
And now the helicopters they are buying from England,
直升机则是向英国购买
thank God they've stopped it.
幸好现在没有再买了
God knows what will happen to the helicopters,
天知道从英国
coming down in India from England.
送来印度的直升机会如何
Like that you see they now are depending on the Third World
就像这样，西方国家的发展进步
for their progress, because they don't know
都依赖「第三世界」国家，因为他们不知道
where to send their own things
他们的机器制造的货物
which are created by their machines.
该卖到哪里去
But the way they do it: I mean, just imagine
他们做事的方式，我是说
the kind of phones we have here, all done by French,
试想想我们的电话，全是法国人制造的
not Indians. Why blame the Indians for that?
不是印度人，为何要为此责备印度人？
Is done by the French, horrid, they have been like this
是法国制造的，真差劲
since long, and they are just the same.
他们一直以来都如此，一直都没变
And again now we have given order to the French,
如今我们仍向他们订购，因为我们以为
because we thought only French can cure
只有法国人才能
the French telephones.
修好法国的电话
I don't know what they are going to do
我不知他们能否
any justice to us or not.
公平的对待我们
So, as that machine is to be worked out,
就如机器需要修理
our own machine is to be worked out;
我们内在的系统也一样要纠正
and that machine is gone downward.
因为它在走下坡
Let us raise it up, upward towards God in surrender,
让我们把它提升起来，在臣服与理解中升向神
in understanding, because you are specially chosen people
因为你们在这方面
in that area.
是特别被挑选出来
Like the lotuses you have to come out of the mud,
就像莲花一样，你要脱离污泥
and don't imbed yourself in the mud more and more.
不要在污泥中越陷越深
Try to push yourself out of that,
尽量把自己挤出来
so that the fragrance of divinity will spread in that mud,
那么神性的芬芳才会弥漫全地
and make the whole of that Western world a beautiful place,
令整个西方社会
beautiful place.
变成美丽的园地
Whatever has been done is done.
过去所发生的是无法挽回
I know one thing: without forgiveness,
但我却知道，没有宽恕
nothing is going to work out. Done is done.
一切都无法改善。已经发生的已经发生了
Erring is human, doesn't matter; whatever is done is done.
犯错是人之常情，不要紧
Whatever they have done is done.
无论他们犯了
It's all right, forgive them.
怎样的过错，原谅他们吧
Forgiveness is the only way they can come up.
宽恕是唯一能提升他们的途径
And when they are forgiven, they have to also realize now
他们获得宽恕后，也必须明白
that we have to rise;
要升进
because the world they have created
因为他们所创造的世界
has really ruined themselves.
确实摧毁了他们
If they rise now the whole place can become fragrant,
如果他们能升进，整个社会都会变得芳香
as I told you, like the lotus that comes out of the mud.
就如我所说，像莲花般出污泥而不染
It's a very wrong idea people have here about the West,
这里的人(印度人)对西方抱有十分错误的想法
that you are the happiest people living around.
以为你们(西方人)是世上最快乐的人
So it is better that we
我们(西方人)最好告诉他们：
tell them that "No, we are not happy there."
不，我们并不快乐
You, what you have got is something precious.
你们拥有的是更珍贵
They also try to follow you,
他们也想跟随你的步伐
and that following is going so far
这样太极端了
that maybe one day you will have to come
或许有朝一日，你们要回来
and teach them Sahaja Yoga.
教导他们霎哈嘉瑜伽
Because they are on the other side of the circle;
因为他们在背道而驰
they are now trying to learn English,
现在他们都想学习英语
master English language, and becoming sahibs.
掌握英语，想变成了爵士
They will come out with tailcoats,
他们甚至学穿燕尾服
and you'll have to tell them that better wear your dresses!
而你要告诉他们最好还是穿印度服饰！
So we should be wise, we should be sensible,
我们要既有智慧又合乎情理
and the stupidity and the silly temperament
必须放弃愚昧的性格
that we have developed, we should give up.
我见到有些人
Suddenly people bubble out, I see that.
如泡沫一样冒起
You see, there's no balance.
你要明白，这是缺乏平衡
The maturity shows when you have a balance.
当你平衡，你的成熟稳重便会流露出来
You should be happy, I know;
你应该感到快乐
but all the time smiling, putting up a show,
但如果你一直笑嘻嘻，装模做样
or sort of suddenly coming out with funny remarks
忽然说些滑稽愚蠢的话
and silly remarks shows you are not matured enough.
这都显示你还未够成熟
You have to mature.
你必须成长成熟
In Sahaja Yoga you mature, and if you do not mature
在霎哈嘉瑜伽你要成长成熟，若你未能做到
then Sahaja Yoga has done no good to you.
那么霎哈嘉瑜伽对你并无任何益处
So you have to be very, very careful about that part.
这点你要十分留意
I hope I've been able to tell you all about it.
我希望我能把想说的全都告诉你
Now what should I tell you ?
马拉地语：我现在该对你说什么？
I was just praising you,
我刚才称赞你们(印度人)
just praising you in front of others.
在他们(西方人)面前称赞你们
I tell them not to behave like stupid people,
我告诉他们不要表现得像蠢人
and for you I must tell you
我必须告诉你们
that you need not blindly imitate them.
不该盲目的模仿他们
Whatever we have got is a very great heritage.
我们已经拥有非常伟大的文化遗产
It should be carefully maintained.
必须用心妥善的保存
By looking at these people, if we try to imitate them
看看这些（西方）人，若我们模仿他们
it will be a foolish behavior on our part.
这会是很愚蠢的行为
Their life is not balanced but has gone to extremes.
他们活得不平衡，偏向极端
I have stayed there for twelve years.
我在那里住了十二年
Thus I have spent a TUP (twelve years)
我花了十二年在那里
so I just wanted to tell you
我只想告诉你们
that you should not blindly follow them.
别盲目地模仿他们
Though old is gold, whatever is oldish  is not good.
虽然古老的都是有价值，但古板陈旧的习俗(马拉地语即junnat)
So oldish is not good.
却并不好
The concept of oldish has also come recently.
古板陈旧的思想概念最近又再出现
For example, from the Muslims we have learnt to harass the women,
例如，我们从穆斯林学会欺压妇女
from the English we have learnt to give dowry.
从英国人学会给予嫁妆
Now we have entered a new rules (of life)
如今我们开始了人生的新规则
and in these new rules we need not give dowry
按照新规则，我们是不用
(to our daughters who are married).
给出嫁的女儿嫁妆
The daughters have been given half the property.
我们的女儿已经获得一半的财产
This system is correct.
女儿应得一半财产的新规则是正确的
But here the daughters will not take, and neither give.
但这里的女儿既不接收也不付出
Thus we should not learn these things from them.
因此我们不应该向他们学习这些习俗
We should keep to our behavior of remaining humble,
我们的言行要保持谦虚简朴
to lead a balanced life as taught to us by our ancestors,
过着先辈所教导的平衡生活
and discard whatever is oldish.
丢弃古板陈旧的习俗
There are many oldish customs lingering in us.
仍有许多古板陈旧的风俗习惯缠绕着我们
For example, the domination of Brahmins in the temples
例如，我们不应接受婆罗门教士
has to be given up.
在庙宇里专横的作风
They all have nicely fooled us.
他们愚弄我们
Secondly, the custom of fasting  has to be given up.
其二，以神的名义来断食的习俗应该丢弃
I've told you hundred of times not to fast,
我已经多次说过别断食
but eat whatever is needed for the body,
要吃身体需要的食物
but people tell Me that "we cannot give up fasting."
但有人却告诉我：「我们无法停止断食。」
But the worst oldish, very dirty habit we have acquired
我们学到最腐旧最肮脏的习惯
is consuming tobacco.
是抽烟
We are not able to give up tobacco,
因为没有足够的意志力
because we do not have enough strength .
我们无法戒掉烟草
Tobacco, mishri (chewing tobacco with lime),
把烟草与Mishri (烟草与柠檬一起咀嚼)
who has brought these things to our country?
是谁把它们带入我国？
From where did the word "tobacco"  come?
"tobacco”(马拉地语是tambakou)这个字从哪里来？
There was no word for tambakou in Sanskrit language.
梵文没有tambakou这个字
We did not cultivate tobacco earlier.
它是从外地引进的
It is the English who have brought it to our country.
我们早年没有种植烟草
The English have brought it here.
是英国人把它带来
That's why we call it tambakou,
故此我们称烟草为tambakou
which has come from the word tobacco.
因为此字源自英文tobacco
Where is the word tambakou in our Marathi language?
马拉地语那有tambakou？
It has been brought here from outside.
它是从外地引进的
Initially the Muslims cultivated it to some extent in our country,
最初穆斯林在我国少量的种植烟草
but these people (English) have brought cigarette
但英国人却把香烟
and other things here on a large scale.
与类似的东西大规模地带来
They use it on a mass scale in their country.
他们在自己的国家也广泛的使用
They have also exported tobacco and ganja (sort of a drug) to China.
他们也把烟草与大麻出口到中国
In our Marathi language I never heard of the word ganja
我从未听过马拉地语有ganja（大麻）
and charras (another sort of drug).
与charras(一种毒品)这些字
If you try to consume ganja  and charras
若你想吸食大麻与charras
you will become like the English.
你会变得像英国人一样
It's up to you to decide.
无论给你什么
Thus whatever is given to us.
你自己来决定吧!
We never had tobacco in our country, you'll be surprised.
你会感到很惊奇，印度以往从未有烟草
There's no word for tobacco in Sanskrit language.
梵文也没有烟草这个词汇
This was brought partly, of course, partly I should say,
引进烟草部分原因是，我要说
by the Muslims and then by the
部分原因是穆斯林把它带来
- the smoking was taught to us only by English.
抽烟却是英国人教我们的
We didn't know that, what was smoking,
我们从前不懂抽烟
we never knew smoking business.
不懂抽烟这玩意
Muslims did have a little bit of it,
穆斯林的确有抽少量的烟
but that started quite late.
但却是近代才开始
But actually this cigarette and this,
事实是香烟和抽烟是
all this has started after the English came in,
在英国人来后才大规模的开展
"making it handy," you see.
他们令烟草「便于使用」
They used to have hookahs.
他们以往抽水烟筒
That was rather difficult to make,
不过那是很难弄的
so they could do it only very little bit.
所以只能少量的吸食
It was a long time back in the Islamic culture.
早年伊斯兰教的文化里已经有这种习惯
But the real, this cigarette business, this ego business
但真正的香烟恶习，这个自我表现的恶习
has come from the English, no doubt about it.
毋庸置疑的是来自英国人
And the Portuguese, Portuguese and the French,
葡萄牙人和法国人
they taught us all these things.
也教我们这些东西
So what I'm trying to tell them,
我是想告诉你们
that whatever is oldish should be given up.
古板陈旧的习俗必须丢弃
Whatever is old is gold,
虽然古老的是有价值
but whatever is oldish that we call as junnat,
但古板陈旧(junnat)的习俗
should be given up.
却必须丢弃
We have the custom of wearing saris with thick borders.
马拉地语：我们(印度人)有穿宽长饰边的纱丽的习俗
This is a very good custom.
这是个好习俗
Thick borders symbolizes maryadas,
宽长的饰边象征分际(maryadas，即界限)
and when we wear saris with thick borders
穿着宽长饰边的纱丽
we stay in our maryadas.
表示我们保持在分际内
Young girls can dress up whatever way they like,
少女可以穿任何她们喜欢的衣饰
but young women, specially married women,
但年轻的妇女，特别是已婚的妇女
should wear saris with thick borders.
应该穿宽长饰边的纱丽
If you give up wearing saris with thick borders
如果你们丢弃这个习俗
then you will lose all the art, all the art.
纱丽的艺术会失传
Weavers will lose all the art of weaving.
织布者也会失去纺织的手艺
If we do not construct our houses as per the old style,
若我们不以旧风格来建筑设计房子
then we will lose all the ancient art of building beautiful houses.
我们会失去古代美丽的建筑艺术
These people like our houses built on the old style,
这些人（西方）喜欢我们的古代建筑风格
not the new style.
不是现代建筑
The reason is that the old style has got beauty in it,
原因是旧的风格很优美
and which might be lost if we built houses anyhow.
如果我们胡乱草率的建筑设计房子，这种优雅的建筑艺术会失传
Even the earlier huts were much better.
即使是旧的茅舍建设也比较好
Instead of this
随此之外
occurring at a later stage,
发生在后阶段的
once we lose all the art in the future it'll be too late.
一旦古代建筑艺术失传，便无法挽回
Thus whatever is our ancient art has to be preserved,
因此，我们必须保留古代艺术的手艺
since it has beauty in it.
因为它很优美
For example we have … type of saris which are called bugdya,
比如，我们有…有一种称为bugdya的纱丽
nowadays the women do not even know the names of these saris.
现代的妇女连这种纱丽的名字也不知道
That's why we should always use the saris
因此我们应该穿着
which have been woven by us. They are good.
自己纺织的纱丽，它们是很好的
I think saris with thick borders suit better for the married women.
我想宽长饰边的纱丽会比较适合已婚妇女
If the saris do not have thick borders, it does not suit them.
若纱丽的饰边不宽长，便不适合她们
Married women should always wear saris with thick borders.
已婚妇女应该常穿宽长饰边的纱丽
It is not an oldish custom, but is a very beautiful custom.
这不单不是陈旧的习俗，还是很优美的习俗
It looks nice, it matches with the women, it looks graceful,
因为它看起来既美丽又适合女性，温文优雅
it has got a look of a well-bred woman.
让妇女穿起来显得又高贵又有教养
It is our culture, which we should not abandon
这是我们的文化，我们不该丢弃我们的文化
and become like them (English).
而变得像他们（西方人）
We should not try to acquire their culture,
我们不应该想学习他们（西方人）的文化
because our culture is very great.
因为我们的文化是很崇高伟大
If we pave our way by understanding
如果我们明白
what has gone wrong with their culture,
他们的文化如何迷失方向
then we can progress well.
便能为我们铺平道路，让我们稳步前进
We can accept their progress in science,
我们可以学习他们科学上的成就
but in doing so if we lose our cultural heritage
但如果这样做会令我们丢弃自己的文化
then we will become like them.
我们会变得像他们一样
They kill their children.
他们杀害自己的子女
Husband and wife cannot stay together even for two years.
夫妻婚后不足两年就闹分手
All of them stay in orphanages, waiting for death to come.
孩子都留在孤儿院里等死
In our society we have to preserve our goodness and kindness.
我们要保存维护我们的社会的美善与仁慈
Instead of that, we have acquired whatever is wrong with others.
但我们却去学习吸收他们的短处
First we had learnt from the Muslims,
我们先从穆斯林学习
and now we are learning from these people.
现在我们又向这些人（西方）学习
If we absorb the dirt from them,
如果我们吸收他们的污秽
how can our houses remain clean?
我们的住所怎能保持清洁干净？
We were supposed to be clean and well-mannerly people,
我们原本是既清洁又有礼貌
and now we have acquired many wrong things from others.
如今我们却向他们吸取了许多错误的东西
Thus we have to abandon these things and cleanse ourselves.
因此，我们必须丢弃这些东西并洁净自己
Now, I've told them what is the importance of puja
我已经告诉他们(西方人)崇拜的重要
but you know these things,
你们(印度人)都懂这些事
so I did not explain it to you.
所以我没有向你们解释
But in puja one should have shraddha,
在崇拜时，我们必须有坚信(shraddha)
and we should not quarrel during the puja.
不应在崇拜时有争执
It does not matter who does the puja
谁带领崇拜都不要紧
since everyone is equally benefited from it,
因为每个人都会平等受益
depending upon the shraddha you have,
全依你的
depending upon the shraddha you have.
坚信而为
Your pitchers will be filled up as much you have the shraddha.
你的水罐会按照你的坚信程度而填满